Guide to the Abraham Yates, Jr. papers, 1604-1825 [bulk 1760-1796]
The New York Public Library. Manuscripts and Archives Division.
- ALPHABETICAL LIST
  - De Lancey, James, addressed to the Corporation of Albany. "I have reason to hope that I shall be enabled to put your town in a batter-posture of defence than it has hitherto been. You are sensible no great dependence is to be had on what the French Indian, February 10, 1755
  - De Lancey, Stephen (Clerk). Order issued to the Sheriff of Albany County to sell the "chattels, lands & Tenements of James Howells" to satisfy his debt to John Magee. Indorsed on the back by Har. Schuyler, Sheriff. D. S. oblong strip, dated June 5, 1767
  - De Lancey, Stephen (Clerk). Order Issued to the Sheriff of Albany County to bring one Banjamin Springer before the next Inferior Court of Common Pleas. A. D. S. oblong strip, dated January 24, 1772
  - De Lancey, Stephen (Clerk). Order Issued to the Sheriff of Albany County to bring John Mohany before the next Inferior Court of Common Pleas. D. S. oblong strip, dated June 5, 1772
  - Douw, Volckert P (judge). Referring to Banjamin Springer's delivery to Bail. D. S. 1 p. quarto, dated September 22, 1772
  - Duane, James. to Abraham Yates Junr. An interesting letter stating the Financier's (Morris') reasons for keeping the offices of Receiver and Loan Officer separate. autograph letter signed 4 p. quarto, dated Philadelphia, September 15, 1782
  - Duncan, John, addressed to Mr. William Corry Esq. In Albany, Refers to the costs of some suit. autograph letter signed 1 p. quarto, dated Schenectady, August 17, 1762
  - Egbertso, Egbert. Complaint against Alexander McLane. D. 2 p. folio. dated Mayor's Court, 1758
  - Federalism. Printed folio Broadside, signed "A Republican Elector, Herkimer, April 27, 1807"
    Vigorous attack upon the Federalists and Burr.
  - Gansevoort, Leonard, addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr., Chairman of the Committee of the City and County of Albany. Transmitting parcells of pamphlets. "The Congress met yesterday morning and proceeded to business. The Ships of War in this Harbour se, February 13, 1776
    Also signed by Henry Oothoudt &. Robert Van Rensselaer.
  - Gansevoort, Leonard. Interesting document, also signed by Philip Livingston (the Signer), Thos. Randall, Gouv. Morris, Thomas Tredwell & Lewis Graham. Summons to Wm. Badkers of Westchester Co., issued by a Committee of the Congress of the Colony of New Yo, June 27, 1776
  - Gansevoort, Leonard. addressed to the newspaper, relative to the superior claims of Abraham Ten Broeck to receive the suffrage of his countrymen rather than Abraham Yates. D 7 p. folio, signed "A Freeholder", in autograph of Leonard Gansevoort, 1786
  - Hardy, Sir Charles, to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr. Refers to the Lieut. Governor's Proclamation & orders Yates to apprehend & carry to Goal all persons in his Bailiwick guilty of Desertion. L. S. 1 p. quarto, dated New York, September 11, 1755
  - Howell, David (Judge), addressed to Honorable Abraham Yates Junr. Esquire, Albany. ''The period will doubtless arrive when the Liberties of this country will fall a sacrifice, but I hope In God that it is not nigh. I hope the Rough Hewer will continue to, July 12, 1785
  - Jansen, Dirck, addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr., Chairman of the Committee at Albany. Asking for six Gentlemen to come down to assist the Militia of Dutchess County in their movement against the disaffected people In his District. D. S. 1 p. folio, May 19, 1776
  - Jay, John (Chief Justice), addressed to The Hon'ble Ab. Yates Esq., Mayor of the City of Albany. Written in the third person and declining Mr. Yates invitation to take breakfast with him. A. D. 1 p. quarto, 1792
  - Jones, Samuel, addressed to Abraham Yates Junr, Esqr., In Albany. "It seems the first Settlers of Albany either conquered or purchased the Lands of the Indians. I suppose they settled as Subjects and under the Protection of the States General in which Cas, July 12, 1771
  - Lansing, Abraham G., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr., New York, Refers to Bills of the New Emission, Loan Office accounts recently examined by Col. Barber and "Certificates and vouchers to the amount of about 50. 000 dollars now In his hands for ap, dated January 25, 1786
  - Lansing, Abraham G., addressed to Mr. Hendrick Gardineer, near Upper Ferry. Refers to the approaching election and the "Great Exertions made by the Manor and Schuyler Interest to prevent the Election of our Old Friend Abraham Yates Jun". "They are only ca, April 19, 1786
  - Lansing, Abraham G., to Abraham Yates Junr, Refers to a Report of the loan Office & mentioning Col. Barber, Mr. Livingston, Mr. Osgood & others. Also mentions Mr. Bancker's serious injury by a fall from a horse. autograph letter signed 4 p. quarto, dated December 3, 1786
  - Lansing, Abraham G., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr., to the care of Wm. Bedlow Esqr., New York. Relating to Loan Office matters, an alternation with the Treasury Board &c. "Barber's situation is perhaps delicate from the prospect he has of continu, dated April 8, 1787
  - Lansing, Abraham G., to Abraham Yates Junr, "The Election for representatives in Assembly has gone against us - Gansevoort, Ten Eyck, Gordon, Van Ingen, Van Orden, Younglove & Sickles. Mrs. Robert Livingston of the Manor is also Dead". autograph letter si, dated June 4, 1737
  - Lansing, Abraham G., addressed to Abraham Yates Junior Esquire, New York. Refers to his brother John Lansing Jr. and Mr. Hamilton, "We have reports here that Mr. Paine is employed to write in favor of the British form of Government and that the system whi, dated August 26, 1767
  - Lansing, Abraham G., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr, Esqr., Poughkeepsie", I am of Opinion that the Measures adopted by Massachusetts Bay will give a tone to the determination of this Important Matter in our Legislature. It is roundly asserted here that, dated January 23, 1788
  - Lansing, Abraham G., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr., to the care of the postmaster, Poughkeepsie. "Politics are still at a stand. A report has been circulated here for some days informing that the Convention of Massachusetts had rejected the Const, dated January 31, 1786
  - Lansing, Abraham G., copy of document addressed to Melancton Smith Esqr. Signed by John Lansing Junr., Jeremiah Van Rensselaer & others, in autograph of Abraham G. Lansing. Requesting that a printer be sent up from New York with his press to look after th, March 1, 1788
  - Lansing, Abraham G., to Abraham Yates Junr. The body of the letter refers to the desire of Lansing and his friends to have an unprejudiced printer in Albany, A postscript in handwriting of and signed by Henry Oothoudt. autograph letter signed 2 p. folio, dated March 2, 1788
  - Lansing, Abraham G., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr, Esqr, to the house of Mr. Powers, Poughkeepsie. "Our Measures have hitherto a most favorable aspect and if we Continue our Exertions we have the greatest prospect of success". autograph letter signed 1, dated March 12, 1788
  - Lansing, Abraham G., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr. in Congress, New York. "The Majority of the Assembly is much greater than we had reason to expect. Communicate the agreeable information to his Excellency, and all our Friends". autograph letter, dated May 27, 1788
  - Lansing, Abraham G., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr, in Congress, New York. Refers to the returns of the recent election & the probability of a Majority in the State. "Should any System be proposed with you it will be well to forward a Sketch of it, dated June 1, 1788
  - Lansing, Abraham G., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr., New York. "It appears to be the opinion of all those whom I have conversed with that the Constitution wl'll be effectually amended previous to it adoption or that it will be Totally rejected", a, dated June 15, 1788
  - Lansing, Abraham G., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr. to the care of Willm. Bedlow Esqr., New York. Refers to the Constitutional Convention. "This Circumstance the Federal gentlemen will no doubt avail themselves of and procractinate the Business as, dated June 22, 1788
  - Lansing, Abraham G., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr, to the care of William Bedlow Esqr., New York, An' interesting letter referring to the Convention. "The Federalists here plume themselves much on the Accession of New Hampshire. They can now give, dated June 29, 1788
  - Lansing, Abraham G., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr., New York. Referring to a quarrel in the city of Albany between the Federalists and the Antis caused by "our Friends and their Antagonists being heated with Liquor. I hope, if the Constitution is, dated July 9, 1788
  - Lansing, Abraham G., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esq., New York, Referring to the Constitutional Convention, "Mr, Jones, it is said, is so much Intimidated by the Threats of the Federalists that he does not any more take an active part, M. Smith is l, dated July 20, 1788
  - Lansing, Abraham G., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr, Esquire, New York
    Refers to the plans of the Federalists in Albany for a celebration in honor of the adoption of the Constitution. "The Bill of Rights which is interwoven with the adoption is considered by the Majority of those to whom I have shewn it as a security against the Encroachments of the Gen., Government", Autograph letter signed 3 p. folio, dated Aug. 3, 1788.
  - Lansing, Abraham G., to William Barber, Original draft of letter. refers to the Commissioners of Forfeitures and also to Mr. Robert Barber, "a young gentleman who served some part of his time with Webster and in the Course of a Month I hope he will be ena, dated August 31, 1738
  - Leonard, Enoch. An acknowledgment of his error as Inspector of Election in refusing Abm. Yates' vote & agreeing to pay all the costs of the suit brought against him by Yates. A. D. S. 1 p. folio, dated July 26, 1791
  - L'Hommedieu, Ezra, addressed to the Honble Abraham Yates Junr. Esquire, Albany. Refers to Yates' desire to obtain the position of Receiver of Taxes; mentions the acknowledgment of American Independence by Holland; also the death of Col, Lawrence near Char, August 2, 1782
  - L'Hommedieu, Ezra, addressed to The Honorable Abraham Yates Junr, Esq., Albany, favoured by Colo, Gonsavolt (Gansevoort), Referring to his demands for condensation for his services as Loan Officer, "The Prospects of Peace are not so favourable as they wer, October 28, 1782
  - Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates, Esq., High Sheriff for the City & County of Albany. Congratulating him on his appointment as Sheriff & requesting that Patrick Magie be retained as "Jaylkeeper" autograph letter signed 1 p, folio, dat, October 7, 1754
  - Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr., High Sheriff of the City & County of Albany. Regretting the appointment of Thos. Morrell as Jail-keeper. "As to Thos. Morrell prhaps you have not heard that I have promised him swiping the, October 21, 1754
  - Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates, Esqr., High Sheriff of the County of Albany. Requesting him to come down to Claverack & bring a "Writt" with him. autograph letter signed 1 p. folio, dated Claverack, December 12, 1754
  - Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr. att Albany. "I am told that there is again a Committee to come from Boston to view and lay out lands, if not in my Manr at least in the neighbourhood. I hope you'll bring more friends along, January 31, 1755
  - Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Esqr. high Sheriff for the City & County of Albany, "On my coming home I was informed that Some of my manor people took 3 new England men in my manor in arms & Carryed them to your Goal by Virtue of a, March 3, 1755
  - Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr., High Sheriff for the City & County of Albany. "With much difficulty I have at Last catched Josiah Loomis, the ringleader and first beginner of the troubles with the Boston Government, He i, April 14, 1755
  - Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Esqr., High Sheriff for the City & County of Albany. "Yours of the 25 ultimo was delivered me yesterday at Tackanick were I have been to turn out my rebellious Tenants & pulled down their houses, which, May 2, 1755
  - Livingston, Robert, Junr., to Abraham Yates Junr. "I am just ready to set out for Boston from whence I have reed 2 letters that my son Phillip is in a declining State. I am much pleased to hear that your Corporation received General Shirly in a Body & tre, July 16, 1755
  - Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Esq., High Sheriff for the City & County of Albany. "I find that you have sent Patrick down to Consult me. I have reason to believe that he does not intend to Execute that precept you mention", autogra, February 9, 1756
  - Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Esqr. att Albany, Relating to some escapes from Goal & the best measures to take for the recapture of one called Shoemaker. autograph letter signed 1 p. folio, dated Manor Livingston, March 31, 1756
  - Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Esqr., High Sheriff of the City & County of Albany. Relating to Judgments against Rebellious Tenants. "We have agreed to give the Govr. L 1800 pr. annum but he Refuses to take it & insists on having L, October 20, 1756
  - Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Esqr., High Sheriff of the City & County of Albany. "I returned last night from New York & shall be glad to see you here the beginning of the next week to Execute the Judgments". autograph letter signe, November 16, 1756
  - Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Esqr., High Sheriff for the City & County of Albany. "I wrote you on my arrival from New York & desiring you to come down to Execute the Judgments of Court for turning my Rebellious Tenants out of poss, November 23, 1756
  - Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Esqr., High Sheriff for the City & County of Albany. "I have been threatened by Van Gelden's Sons to be murdered & burnt down of which I gott an affidavit of a Sheffield man who heard them say it. I he, December 15, 1756
  - Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Esqr., High Sheriff for the City & County of Albany, "Mrs. Livingston told me that She heard the Rebels were again looking out & marking out farms in my mannor". Autograph letter signed 1 p. folio, dat, April 14, 1757
  - Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Esqr., High Sheriff for City & county of Albany. Repeating the request of a former letter & desiring him to come down without any Loss of time. autograph letter signed 1 p, folio, dated Manor Livingsto, April 27, 1757
  - Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr., High Sheriff att Albany. "Sir Charles told me I should apply to you. when ever any attempts were made to Settle or take possession of my Lands". autograph letter signed 1 p. folio, dated M, May 9, 1757
  - Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr, Esqr., High Sheriff for the City & County of Albany. Relating to the release from Goal of John Van Gelden & his son "I fear he will come & burn me down, or waylay & kill me, at least he will join, May 15, 1757
  - Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr., High Sheriff for the City & County of Albany. "I an on my Guard & you'll I suppose not be surprised when you hear that I have Shott him, which I am determined to do the first time I see hi, May 18, 1757
  - Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr, Sheriff of the County of Albany, Enclosing a Proclamation received from Mr. Banyar. autograph letter signed 1 p. quarto, dated Manor Livingston, June 23, 1757
  - Livingston, Robert, Junr., to Abraham Yates Junr. Refers to Peter Dow's Illness & to Col. Schuyler. "I often long to hear the news of your town & of the army, which I most generally have Imperfect". autograph letter signed 1 p. folio, dated Manor Livingst, July 3, 1757
  - Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr., High Sheriff of the City & County of Albany. Refers to John Van Gelden's demand for the restitution of his horse, saddle, bridle, Guns &c. which had bean taken from him when he was committ, July 6, 1757
  - Livingston, Robert, Junr., to Abraham Yates Junr. Interesting letter referring to the French & Indian War. "Am heartily glad to hear that the Summer- set man of war has been so fortunate as to take two French Ships with 300 men & L 89000 Sterling, but I s, July 19, 1757
  - Livingston, Robert, Junr, addressed to Abraham Yates Esqr, att Albany. Inquiring whether Mr. Bleeker intended to come down to run the line for him. autograph letter signed 1 p. folio, dated Manor Livingston, November 5, 1757
  - Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed, to Abraham Yates Junr, Esqr., High Sheriff for the City & County of Albany. Interesting letter relating to the expedition against Ticonderoga. "I see General Abercromby & Lord! How have made application to Coll. Renss, February 17, 1758
  - Livingston, Robert, Junr., to Abraham Yates Junr. "I have been at pickepsinck to assist my Couz's Robert & Henry Livingston in their Election". autograph letter signed 1 p. folio, dated Manor Livingston, January 11, 1759
  - Livingston, Robert, Junr., to Abraham Yates Junr. Interacting letter relating to the politics of Albany. "Both parties have acted unpolitick & without that honour & Generousity with which Citysens ought to treat one the other, at all times & more Especial, February 10, 1759
  - Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Esqr. High Sheriff of City & County of Albany. Refers to the death of "our old friend, Capt. Winne. Lett me know what news you have & where the greatest Strength of our Army is gone, Northward or Westw, June 8, 1759
  - Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Esqr., High Sheriff for the City & County of Albany. Interesting letter relating to the French & Indian War. "I am in a Continual dread least I should hear of the French Fleets getting to Quebec before, June 15, 1759
  - Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Esqr., High Sheriff for City & County of Albany. Interesting letter relating to the French & Indian War. "I beg you to write me the particulars of Niagara & how it came about that Sir William, had the, August 6, 1759
  - Livingston, Robert, Junr., to Abraham Yates Junr. Interesting letter referring to Gen. Amherst, Sir. William Johnson, Gen. Wolfe, Admiral Rodney & others. "In my opinion if we do not take Canada we shall gitt very little by this war". autograph letter sig, August 30, 1759
  - Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr, Esqr, att Albany. "I have seen the article of Surrender of Quebec in our papers, which; are also Extraordinary and moth of a piece with those of Gardaloupe, neither of which please me. I do not t, November 24, 1759
  - Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr. att Albany, Refers to his lot in the "Sarightoga Pattent". "The French officers make a long tarry on our frontiers, provisions are more plenty there then at Canada". Autograph letter 6. 1 p, January 3, 1760
  - Livingston, Robert, Junr., to Abraham Yates Junr, Referring to Yates having been removed from office by his enemies, "They now begin with me, the Great & mighty Coll, has seared upon my horses & Sleds". autograph letter signed 1 p. folio, dated Manor Livi, January 24, 1760
  - Livingston, Robert, Junr., to Abraham Yates Junr. "God Grant we may Soon take all Canada & keep it while the world Stands, that we may be relieved from Sundry pette Tyrants who rule with a Rod of Iron the best Subjects the King of Great Brittain has in al, February 8, 1760
  - Livingston, Robert, Junr., to Abraham Yates Junr. Refers to the Albany Library. "God Grant us Success that the Enemy may be obliged to Sue for a peace before the End of this year". autograph letter signed 1 p. folio, dated Manor Livingston, February 29, 1760
  - Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr, Esqr. att Albany, Very interesting letter containing war news, "I heard that the French have Raised the Siege of Quebec on the appearance of our fleet, I shall order a good fat Oxen to be brought, May 30, 1760
  - Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Mr. Abraham Yates Junr., Merchant in Albany. Referring to the Albany election, certain lands in Saratoga Patent, making mention of Col, Bradstreet, the Bleeckers, Ten Rroecks and De Ridders, & closing; as follows: -, July 17, 1760
  - Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr. att Albany, Refers to the damage to crops paused by heavy rains all the way from Fishkill up to Albany. "I expect our Army is now in motion. This is a time we ought above all others to humb, August 11, 1760
  - Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Mr. Abraham Yates Junr. att Albany. Refers to the good news that "our Armies are now in possession of all Canada". Also mentions Yates' desire to again obtain the office of Sheriff. autograph letter signed 1 p. foli, September 3, 1760
  - Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Esqr. att Albany. "I have this day, wrote to my Brother Philip & William to wate on his Honr. the President and to desire the favour of him in my name to appoint you Sheriff for the Ensuing year". auto, September 9, 1760
  - Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Mr. Abraham Yates Junr., Merchant In Albany. "I Long to hear what voyages your Albany Gentlemen have made to Canada. I also want to know how the Troops are to be disposed of now the war is at an End in our- Quarter", October 13, 1760
  - Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr, Esqr. att Albany. Refers to the sale of lands in the Saratoga Patent by the Bleeckers, Mr. Ten 'Broeck & Schuyler & "your old uncle Killiaen". "I imagine your City must enlarge that way, while no, November 7, 1760
  - Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Esq, att Albany. "But how your uncle Killiaen will sell any I am at a loss to know, as I heard sometime ago that there was some difficulty in his Tittle". autograph letter signed 1 p. folio, dated Mano, November 13, 1760
  - Livingston, Robert, Junr. addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr. att Albany. Refers to Killiaen De Ridder's title to lands in the Saratoga Patent. "I hear It hinted from New York that we are going to have an expedition this winter to the Mississippi - tha, December 10, 1760
  - Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr, Esqr, In Albany, Refers to a petition addressed by the Corporation of the City of Albany to "the President & Council". "I Congratulate you on the Victory Lately gained by the King of Prussia, thi, January 22, 1761
  - Livingston, Robert, Junr., to Abraham Yates Junr. Referring to the election in Albany & mentioning various candidates, "If you are Inclinable to Sett up with Mr. Abraham Ten Broeck, whom I Look upon to be without any flattery the two best Qualifyed in you, February 4, 1761
  - Livingston, Robert, Junr., to Abraham Yates Junr. Referring to the coming Election & the difference of opinion existing between Yates & Ten Broeck, Mentions Sir William Johnson, "who undoubtedly has great Interest". "As for my part while my friends are so, February 6, 1761
  - Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr. att Albany